<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chifra on</title><link>/docs/chifra/</link><description>Recent content in Chifra on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/chifra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Chifra</title><link>/docs/chifra/introducing-chifra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/introducing-chifra/</guid><description>Similar to git, TrueBlocks has an overarching command called chifra that gives you access to all of the other subcommands.
Type:
chifra You will see a long list of commands similar to this
Usage: chifra command Purpose: Access to all TrueBlocks tools (chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help for more). Where: ACCOUNTS list list every appearance of an address anywhere on the chain export export full detail of transactions for one or more addresses monitors add, remove, clean, and list address monitors names query addresses or names of well known accounts abis fetches the ABI for a smart contract CHAIN DATA blocks retrieve one or more blocks from the chain or local cache transactions retrieve one or more transactions from the chain or local cache receipts retrieve receipts for the given transaction(s) logs retrieve logs for the given transaction(s) traces retrieve traces for the given transaction(s) when find block(s) based on date, blockNum, timestamp, or 'special' CHAIN STATE state retrieve account balance(s) for one or more addresses at given block(s) tokens retrieve token balance(s) for one or more addresses at given block(s) ADMIN status report on the status of the TrueBlocks system serve serve the TrueBlocks API using the flame server scrape scan the chain and update the TrueBlocks index of appearances init initialize the index of appearances by downloading Bloom filters pins manage pinned index of appearances and associated Bloom filters OTHER quotes freshen and/or display Ethereum price data explore open an explorer for a given address, block, or transaction slurp fetch data from EtherScan for any address You may get more help on any command by typing chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help.</description></item><item><title>Some Chifra Examples</title><link>/docs/chifra/using-chifra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/using-chifra/</guid><description>A few more examples in more detail.
Getting Help Every chifra sub-command comes with an associated help page. To get help for chifra itself, simply type
chifra A long list of commands should show. (If you have trouble, see the Installation page.)
To get help for a specific command, type
chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help To get more detailed help, type
chifra &amp;lt;cmd&amp;gt; --help --verbose 2 Getting System Status The chifra command gives you access to all of TrueBlocks' functionality.</description></item><item><title>Accounts</title><link>/docs/chifra/accounts/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 21:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/accounts/</guid><description>This group of commands is at the heart of TrueBlocks. They allow you to produce and analyze transactional histories for a given Ethereum address.
You may also name addresses; grab the ABI file for a given address; add, delete, and remove monitors, and, most importantly, export transactional histories to various formats, This includes re-directing output to remote or local databases.
chifra list chifra list takes one or more addresses, queries the index of appearances, and builds TrueBlocks monitors.</description></item><item><title>Chain Data</title><link>/docs/chifra/chaindata/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 21:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/chaindata/</guid><description>The chaindata tools extract raw blockchain data directly from the node. You may extract block data, transactional data, receipts, logs, and traces. Each tool has it own set of options, allowing you to get exactly the data that you want.
chifra blocks The chifra blocks tool retrieves block data from your Ethereum node or, if previously cached, from the TrueBlocks cache. You may specify multiple blocks per invocation.
By default, chifra blocks queries the full transactional details of the block (including receipts).</description></item><item><title>Chain State</title><link>/docs/chifra/chainstate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 01:48:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/chainstate/</guid><description>The two tools in this group deal with the Chain State. As chain state data concerns balances and byte code. it is distinct from Chain Data, which concerns things like blocks, transactions, or traces.
The two tools are chifra state and chifra tokens. The first allows you to query account balances, the byte code of a smart contract (if available), the nonce, and other information about an address. The second tool, chifra tokens, deals with ERC20 and ERC721 token balances and other data.</description></item><item><title>Admin</title><link>/docs/chifra/admin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 21:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/admin/</guid><description>The Admin component allows you to query the status of the TrueBlocks system. You may query the status; query for information about TrueBlocks caches; control the creation, sharing, and pinning of the TrueBlocks index of appearances; and even serve the data through an API. See our API documentation for more information.
chifra status The chifra status program allows you to manage the various TrueBlock caches. You may list all of the caches, some of the cache, or even individual caches either in terse or full detail.</description></item><item><title>Other</title><link>/docs/chifra/other/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 01:48:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/chifra/other/</guid><description>These commands call some useful miscellaneous tools:
chifra quotes, a rudimentary pricing tool, chifra explore a quick way to open a blockchain explorer, ethslurp an older tool that lets you call data from EtherScan. (This has issues of ceentralization and data quality, see explanation in its section). 👉 Note: some of these tools, like `ethslurp`, require an EtherScan key. Follow these instructions to add a key to your config</description></item></channel></rss>