<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Do I need a node?</title><link>/docs/prologue/do-i-need-a-node/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/do-i-need-a-node/</guid><description>And if you have a node, its preferably with Erigon.
Some benefits of TrueBlocks can be realized only when a user has their own node. Having a node lets users:
Limit queries to the node on their machine Use the node to build a local index Query data directly from the top of the chain Setting up a node is not as hard as many people think, but it does require two TBs of storage and some good hardware.</description></item><item><title>Install TrueBlocks</title><link>/docs/prologue/installing-trueblocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2020 13:59:39 +0100</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/installing-trueblocks/</guid><description>These instructions assume you can navigate directories with the command line and edit configuration files. If you need help with a step, see the installation&amp;rsquo;s troubleshooting section.
Quick Install Install dependencies
☑ Install the latest version of Go. ☑ Install the other dependencies with your command line: build-essential git cmake python python-dev libcurl3-dev clang-format jq. Compile from the codebase
git clone -b develop https://github.com/trueblocks/trueblocks-core cd trueblocks-core mkdir build &amp;amp;&amp;amp; cd build cmake .</description></item><item><title>Get the Index</title><link>/docs/prologue/how-can-i-get-the-index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:19:51 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/how-can-i-get-the-index/</guid><description>If you want to&amp;hellip; and you don&amp;rsquo;t mind&amp;hellip; then use&amp;hellip; minimize the size of the data stored locally and you want to get started faster&amp;hellip; slower first-time queries on new addresses, an index that&amp;rsquo;s slightly behind the head of the chain, an index created by someone else&amp;hellip; chifra init maximize the speed of first-time queries for new addresses&amp;hellip; longer initial setup time, ~70 GB of local storage, an index that&amp;rsquo;s slightly behind the head of the chain, an index created by someone else&amp;hellip; chifra pins --init_all have a fully-local index, built directly from your own node, that stays up with the chain and maximizes the speed of your queries&amp;hellip; two to three days setup time and running your own local tracing / archive node (such as dAppnode)&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>Install the Explorer Browser app</title><link>/docs/prologue/install-explorer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 08:01:07 -0300</pubDate><guid>/docs/prologue/install-explorer/</guid><description>First, make sure that you have the chifra-core backend up and running, then run the application from a clone of the explorer repo.
PreReqs. Set up the trueblocks backend using the chifra installation instructions In a terminal window, run the command chifra serve Install from the repo In a new terminal (keep the chifra serve process running)
git clone git@github.com:TrueBlocks/trueblocks-explorer.git cd trueblocks-explorer cp .env.example .env yarn yarn develop Open your browser, and access the app from localhost:1234.</description></item></channel></rss>